Hi there, today we'll talk about some of our productivity
tips and features in VS code. We want to make
it easy for you to get started, get comfortable and
get coding. The first thing we'll talk about is the
command palette. The command palette is the easiest way to
find something in BS code. If you're ever looking for
a feature or a shortcut or an action from an
extension, go to view.
Command palette.
Or use the keyboard shortcut.
In the command palette you'll also see the associated keyboard
shortcut for every command that has one.
Next I'll show you how to quick open a file
on Windows control. P will show you your recently opened
files and you can search for any file in the
repository you currently have open. Selecting the file will open
it in a new editor. You can also add a
colon after the name of a file and type A
line number and a new editor window will open. Add
that line number.
You can do the same thing with the @ to
go to a symbol in a file.
Type the question mark to view command to questions that
might be useful to you.
Repeat the quick open keyboard shortcut to cycle quickly between
recently opened files.
You can also open multiple files from quick open by
pressing the right arrow key. This will open the currently
selected file in the background and you can continue selecting
files from quick open.
Multi Cursor selection is another really useful editing feature on
Windows. You can all Click to add a new cursor
anywhere in your file.
You can also set cursors above or below your current
position using control alt up arrow or control Alt down
Arrow. You can even add additional cursors to all occurrences
of the current selection with shift control.
This is useful for editing or deleting multiple occurrences of
repeated code in a file.
This one's really simple, but I highly encourage you to
take a second to do it. Go to file.
Autosave and make sure you have autosave turned on.
A couple of other settings you can configure are format
on type and format on Paste set editor format on
type to true to auto format your text each time
you type A line. You can also set editor format
on paste to true to format your text whenever you
paste new text into your editor.
Finally, let's talk a little bit about Intellisense. Intellisense is
a general term for various code editing features like code
completion and quick info. It's provided out of the box
for some languages in VS code, but you can install
language extensions to have richer Intellisense for specific languages. Let
me show you an example with JavaScript. If I start
typing the name of a variable, it will show me
what variables are available in this file. If I select
one, then type.
I'll be given a list of all the properties and
methods accessible to that variable. I can pick a method
and go to add a parameter which will then show
me info about that parameter.
You can trigger and tell a sense in any editor
window by typing^ space or by typing a trigger character
such as the dot character in JavaScript. Check out our
Intellisense documentation for more in depth information. I hope you
enjoyed following along and learned something new. For more information,
check out our documentation at code.visualstudio.com. Happy coding.